

NIYATI PATEL

Electronics and

Telecommunications Engineer

Frontend Web Developer

- © 2B/504 Umiya Nagar Society, Goregaon East, Mumbai - 400063
- ☑ patelnitie@gmail.com
- **&** +91 9082431142

#### SOCIAL

- in @niyati-mukesh-patel
- @NiyatiMPatel

#### PROFILE

Electronics and telecommunications engineer, frontend web/ UI developer, Udemy certified React developer, AWS certified developer associate and Cloud Solutions architect, able to release projects from the ground up. With a demonstrated history of working in the electronics telecommunications industry and retail sector, acquired ability to work efficiently with crossfunctional teams in ensuring operational, service, change management and customer experience excellence.

#### EDUCATION

WEB DESIGN AND DEVELOPMENT (MERN STACK DEVELOPMENT)

TryCatch Classes
06/2022 - Current

## **PROJECTS**

# 🕨 Login Page | November 2021

Simple login page using HTML5 and CSS3. Uses HTML5 validation for username and password. Redirects to successful page when clicked login button.

View Project

# Dribble Card Design | November 2021

Single static card design using HTML5 and CSS3.

View Project

# Onetown (Multiple Pages) | February 2022 |

Static website using HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript. Allows users to navigate between pages by clicking on navigation menu options. Added background image carousel and featured images slick slider for enhanced user interface.

View Project

## Expense Tracker | March 2022

ReactJS based expense tracker app. Fully responsive and interactive app. Uses dummy dataset, accepts and temporarily stores and displays user inputs.

View Project

# Food Order App | April 2022

ReactJS based food ordering app. Fully responsive and interactive app.

Connected to Firebase Realtime Database to fetch food menu and post order confirmed.

View Project

# FitGym Template Clone Assignment @ TryCactch Classes | July 2022

Laptop and Mobile responsive website using HTML5 and CSS3.

View Project

# Start Bootstrap Template Clone Assignment @ TryCactch Classes | August 2022

Device responsive website using HTML5, CSS3 and Bootstrap5.

View Project

# Vendor – E-Commerce Bootstrap Template Clone Assignment @ TryCactch Classes | August 2022

Device responsive website using HTML5 and CSS3.

View Project

## CERTIFICATES

React - The complete guide (including Hooks, React Router, Redux) | May 2022

View Certificate

# MASTER OF ENGINEERING (TELECOMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING)

Melbourne Institute of Technology 11/2016 - 07/2018

# BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING (ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING)

Atharva College of Engineering 07/2012 - 05/2015

# DIPLOMA OF ENGINEERING (ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING)

Thakur Polytechnic 07/2009 - 05/2012

## SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS3
- Bootstrap5
- Javascript
- Github
- Firebase

- ReactJS, Router, Redux
- Amazon Web Service
- Cisco routing and switching
- Microsoft office suit

## AWS Solutions Architect - Associate | February 2021

View Certificate

# AWS Developer - Associate | November 2020

View Certificate

#### EXPERIENCE

#### RETAIL ASSISTANT

06/2020 to 07/2021 | Moorabbin Fresh Farmer Wholesale Market | Melbourne, Victoria, Australia

- Scan and weigh groceries, fresh produce and ensure correct price is charged
- Process EFTPOS transactions, including cash and credit purchases or refunds
- Answer customers' questions, provide information on procedures fulfilling requests
- Work closely with Store Manager to solve problems and handle customer concerns

#### TELECOMMUNICATIONS ENGINEER

02/2018 to 04/2020 | Exel Galaxy Technology Services Pty Ltd | Melbourne, Victoria, Australia

- Onsite FTTC, FTTN, HFC installation, deployment, line inspection and service restoration from construction and design faults ensuring QA, OH&S
- Analyse new telecommunications sites by locating sites and following through to approval
- Review project deliverables, technical standards and initiate appropriate corrective actions
- Record project risks, issues, internal and external project status and coordinate timely resolutions
- Maintain documentation for all telecommunication systems to stay abreast of new technology standards

## TELECOMMUNICATIONS ENGINEER INTERN

11/2017 to 01/2018 | Exel Galaxy Technology Services Pty Ltd | Melbourne, Victoria, Australia

- Establish positive customer relations and coordinate with team members to ensure requests and questions were handled appropriately
- Co-ordinate with project engineering team to prepare work plans, schedules and allocation
- Offer engineering support to FTTC and FTTN copper team during commissioning phase of project

- Provide assistance with documentation, project deliverables including artefact sorting, logging and work order creation.
- Create new and on-going performance assessment of project, issues, construction crew